SALEEM KARKABI

United Arab Emirates, Abu Dhabi, Al Nahyan, Jarrah Street, Villa 9 · +971506660187 saleemkarkabi@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/saleem-karkabi-31566a206

Hardworking quick learner prepared for any new task & challenge with 3+ years' experience in steel product manufacturing, IT, & software development. Successful in learning new technologies & procedures, such as new programming languages, light building material manufacturing, & coordinating within large teams on inter-divisional tasks & projects. With knowledge in both software development & factory production, capable of exploring problems from multiple perspectives & integrate both software development & production practices to create unique solutions.

EXPERIENCE

2018 - CURRENT

IN HOUSE SYSTEMS DEVELOPER, TECHNICAL METAL INDUSTRIAL

- Design, code, & support software solutions to streamline factory tasks
- Design, code & support software solutions to facilitate internal invoicing between different departments
- Integrating existing excel data into SQL
- Developing simple software solutions to aide in factory reporting

2019 - 2020

PRODUCTION CONTROLLER, TECHNICAL METAL INDUSTRIAL

- Examined incoming materials to verify order specifications
- Facilitated material processing & distribution to appropriate divisions
- Coordinated internal material transfer between divisions
- Coordinated production stock & procedures between all divisions for migration to new ERP system

2020 – CURRENT

TECHNICAL INTERNAL AUDITOR, TECHNICAL METAL INDUSTRIAL

- Inspecting factory floors to ensure proper production practices
- Conducting safety & health inspections on factory floors to ensure factories are following standard OHS protocols
- Review production documentation making sure documentation matches real production
- Recommending & implementing new production procedures to facilitate client requirements

2018 – CURRENT

COMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR, FREELANCE

- Providing a basic understanding of datatypes, logical operators, & entry control loops
- Working with students to complete both academic assignments & personal projects
- Exposing students to software testing technologies such as Junit
- Primarily teach students how to code in Java, but provide different languages on request

EDUCATION

2013 - 2018

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, CARLETON UNIVERSITY

Relevant Coursework:

- Object Oriented Software Engineering
- Database Management Systems
- Operating Systems
- Real-Time Concurrent Systems
- Applied Cryptography
- Abstract Data Types & Algorithms
- Design & Analysis of Algorithms 1

2020 - 2021

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE HONORS WITH CONCENTRATION IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING & MINOR IN SOCIOLOGY, CARLETON UNIVERSITY

Relevant Coursework:

- Human Computer Interaction
- Software Quality Assurance
- The Software Economy & Project Management

SKILLS

- Programming (Proficient):
 - Java
 - MySQL
 - Visual Basic for Applications
 - JavaScript
 - HTML & CSS
- Programming (Capable):
 - Swift
 - Kotlin
 - C
 - C++
 - Python
- Languages:
 - Fluent English
 - Conversational Arabic

- Operating Systems:
 - Windows 10/8/7
 - Mac OS
- Technologies:
 - Balsamiq Wireframe Prototyping
 - JUnit
 - Cypress
 - Selenium
 - JavaFX
 - Cucumber
 - Node.js
 - Express.js
 - Handlebars.js
 - MongoDB
 - Git

INTERESTS

- Boxing
- Skating
- Hockey
- Comics
- Sociology